Mss.Ms.Coll.109
American Philosophical Society
- Works By, 12.75 linear feet
  - Marriage- A Cultural Perspective, Drafts, 1956; undated; 2 items (Box 73)
  - Marrying for the Right Reasons, Draft, 1958; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Maturity, Notes, undated; 20 items (Box 73)
  - Medical Education in the Preclinical Years, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Medicine, Notes, undated; 6 items (Box 73)
    Includes a marked up, but incomplete galley copy of the article with significant notes.
  - Memo on Meeting at 20th Century- Fox, Los Angeles, 15 May 1980, Draft, 1 item (Box 73)
  - Menstruation, Notes, undated; 30 items (Box 73)
  - Menstruation, Correspondence, 1982; 2 items (Box 73)
  - Menstruation, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Mental Illness, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 73)
  - Methodology, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 73)
  - Metopism, Notes, undated; 45 items (Box 73)
  - Metopism, Correspondence, 1934; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Mind and the Body, Draft, 1926; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Mind and the Brain, Draft, 1926; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Mind of the Skin, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Misc. Lecture Questions, undated; 120 items (Box 73)
  - Misc. Notes, undated; 426 items (Box 74)
    1 of 2 folders.
  - Misc. Notes, undated; 426 items (Box 74)
    2 of 2 folders.
  - Misquoted Scientists Respond, Draft, 1981; 1 item (Box 73)
    Montagu is a contributor to this work, edited by Dr. John R. Cole.
  - MOM Interviews, Dr. Ashley Montagu, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Mutilated Humanity, Drafts, undated; 3 items (Box 73)
  - My Conception of the Nature of Human Nature, Draft, 1979; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Myelinization and Behavior, Draft, 1949; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Myth of Blood, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Mythology, Notes, undated; 13 items (Box 73)
  - Mythology, Correspondence, 1988-1991; 12 items (Box 73)
  - The Natchez Innominate Bone, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Natchez Pelvis, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Native Americans, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 73)
  - Natural Selection and Civilization, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
    Co-authored by Theodosius Dobzhansky.
  - Natural Selection and Man's Relative Hairlessness, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Natural Selection and the Form of the Breast in the Human Female, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Natural Selection and the Mental Characters of Mankind, Correspondence, 1965; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Natural Selection and the Mental Characters of Mankind, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Natural Selection and the Origin and Evolution of Weeping in Man, Draft, 1960; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Natural Superiority of Women, Correspondence, 1951-1979; 37 items (Box 73)
  - The Natural Superiority of Women, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Natural Superiority of Women, Review, 1977; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Nature of Human Aggression, Reviews, 1976-1982; 14 items (Box 73)
  - The Nature of Human Nature, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - The Nature of Humanism, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Nature, Nuture and Nutrition, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
  - Neanderthal and the Modern Type of Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Negritues, Notes, undated; 11 items (Box 75)
  - Negro Educational Capacity- A Scientist's View, Draft, 1956; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Neoteny, Notes, undated; 19 items (Box 75)
  - Neoteny, Correspondence, 1987; 1990; 2 items (Box 75)
  - Nescience, Science and Psycho-Analysis, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - New Directions in Human Communication, Outline, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - New Discoveries in Human Heredity, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - New Frontiers in Education, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - A New Theory Concerning the Origin of Speech, Correspondence, 1963; 1966; 5 items (Box 75)
  - Newbold Syndrome, Introduction, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Newborn Baby is the Best Medicine for Mother, Abstract, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Noise, Notes, undated; 35 items (Box 75)
  - Noise, Correspondence, 1988; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Nonesense Triumphant, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - A Note on the Pigmentation of the Palms and Soles as Compared with the Rest of the Body, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Notes, Antient Metaphysics, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Nudism, Correspondence, 1990-1994; 13 items (Box 75)
  - Nudism and Nature, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Nudity & Body Acceptance, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Obesity and the Evolution of Man, Correspondence, 1965; 1966; undated; 10 items (Box 75)
  - Obesity and the Evolution of Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Odors, Notes, undated; 4 items (Box 75)
  - Odors, Correspondence, 1969-1976; 7 items (Box 75)
  - Of Human Nature, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Asking Questions, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Being A Judge, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Being Certain, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Being Human, Correspondence, 1950-1986; 24 items (Box 75)
  - On Being Human, Draft, 1951; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Being Human, Reviews, 1950-1967; 11 items (Box 75)
  - On Being Human About On Being Human, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Darwin's The Descent of Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Eating and Overeating, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Love, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Our Reactions to the Disabled, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Swearing, Draft, 1928; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Talking to Some Purpose, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On the Distinction Between Disease and Disorder, Notes, 1928-1933; undated; 9 items (Box 75)
  - On the Distinction Between Disease and Disorder, Correspondence, 1962; 3 items (Box 75)
  - On the Distinction Between Disease and Disorder, Drafts, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On the Origin of Law, Notes, undated; 6 items (Box 75)
  - On the Origin of Law, Correspondence, 1996; 2 items (Box 75)
  - On the Origin of Law, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On the Origin of the Present Variety of Skin and Eye Pigmentation, Hair Colour and Hair Form in Men, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On the Relation Between Body Size, Walking Activity, and the Origin and Evolution of Social Life, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On the Threshold, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Yawning, Correspondence, 1962-1984; 25 items (Box 75)
  - On Yawning, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - On Yawning, Review, 1963; 1 item (Box 75)
  - One-Egge Twin Studies, Draft, 1972; 1 item (Box 75)
  - One World or None, Atomic Energy: Control or Perish, Notes, undated; 22 items (Box 75)
  - One World or None, Atomic Energy: Control or Perish, Correspondence, 1946; undated; 46 items (Box 75)
  - One World or None, Atomic Energy: Control or Perish, Philip Regan Associates, Inc, 1949; undated; 3 items (Box 75)
  - One World or None, Atomic Energy: Control or Perish, Drafts, 1946; undated; 3 items (Box 75)
  - One World or None, Atomic Energy: Control or Perish, Review, 1946; 1 item (Box 75)
  - One World or None, World Co-Operation Or..., Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Orientation of the Skull, A Proposal for a New Base-Line, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Origin and Evolution of Laughter, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Origin and Evolution of Man Physically and Culturally, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Origin an Evolution of Weeping in Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Origin and Nature of Social Life and the Biological Basis of Cooperation, Draft, 1949; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Origin and Significance of Neonatal and Infant Immaturity in Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Origin of Social Life and Cooperation and the Future of Mankind, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - The Origin of Subincision in Australia, Draft, 1937; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Orthodontics, Notes, undated; 2 items (Box 75)
  - Other Things Being Equal, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Our Changing Concept of Human Nature, Draft, 1952; 1 item (Box 75)
  - Paget's Disease (Osteitis deformans) and Heredity, Draft, 1949; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Palate, Notes, undated; 13 items (Box 76)
  - Panel Discussion on "Social Aspects of Anxiety" in Symposium "Anxiety and a Decade of Tranquilizer Therapy," Abstract, 1964; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Parenting, Notes, undated; 6 items (Box 76)
  - Parenting, Correspondence, 1960-1969; undated; 7 items (Box 76)
  - Parents are the Principal Cause of Juvenile Delinquency, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Paul Du Chaillu, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 76)
  - The Peace of the World, Draft, 1958; 1 item (Box 76)
  - The Pearl, Drafts, 1976; undated; 2 items (Box 76)
  - Personal Library Catalog, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
    Listing of books by Montagu and others, in Montagu's possession.
  - Phavorinus, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 76)
  - Physical Anthropology, Notes, undated; 19 items (Box 76)
  - Physical Anthropology, Drafts, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Physical Anthropology and Anatomy, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Physiology and the Origins of the Menstrual Prohibitions, Draft, 1940; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Pigmentation, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Piltdown Man, Notes, undated; 16 items (Box 76)
  - Piltdown Man, Correspondence, 1949-1991; 39 items (Box 76)
  - Piltdown Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - The Piltdown Man Mandible and Cranium, Draft, 1951; 1 item (Box 76)
  - The Piltdown Nasal Turbinate: Some Questions, Drafts, undated; 4 items (Box 76)
  - The Place of Youth in Today's Society, Draft, 1966; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Plan and Budget for Science Supplement of Saturday Review, Draft, 1952; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Play, Notes, undated; 24 items (Box 76)
  - Play, Correspondence, 1994; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Play or Murder?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Poetry, 1931-1970; 1995; 1997; 82 items (Box 76)
    Includes three handwritten, bound, collections of poetry by Ashley Montagu, as well as loose items.
  - Population, Draft, 1963; 1 item (Box 76)
  - The Population Explosion, Draft, 1963; 1 item (Box 76)
  - The Population Problem, Draft, 1965; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Porpoises as Torpedoes, Correspondence, 1962-1974; undated; 74 items (Box 76)
  - Porpoises as Torpedoes, Letter to Editor, Draft, 1966; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Preface to the Third Edition, "What a unique and wonderful experience it is to have a baby and be a mother!," Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Prejudice, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 76)
  - Premaxilla, Notes, undated; 31 items (Box 77)
  - Premaxilla, Correspondence, 1934-1995; 18 items (Box 77)
  - The Premaxilla and the Ancestry of Man, Drafts, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - The Premazilla in the Primates, Proposal, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Prenatal Influences, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Prenatal Influences, Correspondence, 1992; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Prenatal Influences, Reviews, 1962-1977; 11 items (Box 77)
  - Pre-Patriarchal Religion, Foreword, Correspondence, 1996; undated; 7 items (Box 77)
  - Pre-Patriarchal Religion, Foreword, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Press Release, Psychology Today Interview on the Elderly, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - The Prevalence of Nonsense, Correspondence, 1967, 132 items (Box 77)
  - The Prevalence of Nonsense, Correspondence, 1966, 65 items (Box 77)
  - The Prevalence of Nonsense, Correspondence, 1957-1965, undated, 37 items (Box 77)
  - The Prevalence of Nonsense, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - The Prevalence of Nonsense, Reviews, 1967; 1968; 9 items (Box 77)
  - The Primate Brain, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Primates, Correspondence, 1948; 3 items (Box 77)
  - Primitive Medicine, Notes, undated; 2 items (Box 77)
  - Primitive Medicine, Draft, 1946; 1949; 2 items (Box 77)
  - Primitive Mentality, Drafts, 1924; 1989; 2 items (Box 77)
  - Principles of Human Relations, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Privacy, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 77)
  - The Private Language of Love, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Problem of Race in the Teaching Biologist, vol. IX (No. 2), Draft, 1939; 1 item (Box 78)
  - The Procreative Theories of Nonliterate Peoples, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - The Proper Study of Race, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Psychoanalysis, Correspondence, 1947; 4 items (Box 78)
  - Psychological Aspects of Race Prejudice, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Psychology, Notes, undated; 14 items (Box 78)
  - Psychology, Correspondence, 1974-1994; 9 items (Box 78)
  - The Psychology of Circumcision, Foreword, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Pterion, Notes, undated; 42 items (Box 78)
  - The Public Be Sold, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Pyramidalis, Notes, undated; 50 items (Box 78)
  - Pyramidalis, Correspondence, 1938; 1939; 2 items (Box 78)
  - Race, Notes, undated; 50 items (Box 78)
  - Race, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 78)
  - Race and IQ, Contributing Authors, Frank Livingstone and C. Loring Brace, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Race and IQ, Introduction, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 78)
  - Race and IQ, Review, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Race and the Modern World, Table of Contents, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Race Between Education and Catastrophe, The, Submitted Articles, 1991; 38 items (Box 78)
    Second edition of Montagu's 1958 work entitled _Education and Human Relations_. Contains a cover letter and a listing of the articles, as well as 36 submitted articles, all of which are reprints of previous works.
    Scope and Contents note #2
    List of articles: Education, Humanity, and Technology; Mind, Communication, and Evolution; Childhood's Promises; The Origin and Significance of Neonatal & Infant Immaturity; Sociogenic Brain Damage; Our Reactions to the Disabled; Art as Integrity; Art, Curriculum, and Culture; The Urge to Acquire Kids; Civilization: A Race Between Education and Catastrophe; Educators: The Unacknowledged Legislators of the World; Humankind; Moral Environment; What Every Child & Adult Should Know About Race; Play or Murder?; Don't Be Adultish; Learning Influences Human Behavior; The Need for Sensitivity; My Conception of Human Nature; The Salutation of the Dawn; To Think and to Feel; The Meaning of Education; The Need for Sensitivity (duplicate); Social & Cultural Forces The Effects on Institutions & Children; Growing Young; Is Man Innately Aggressive; The Origin and Nature of Social Life and the Biological Basis of Cooperation; The New Litany of 'Original Sin'; The Unacknowledged Legislators of the World (duplicate); Time Binding & The Concept of Culture; As If Living and Loving Were One; Learning Influences Human Behavior (duplicate); Has Chastity a Chance at College?; The Current Values & Changing Needs of Youth; The College in the Crosscurrents of Change.
  - The Race Problem: What is the Solution?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
    Galley copy
  - Race Relations and the Publicist, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Race, Science, and Humanity, Draft, 1968; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Race: The History of an Idea, Draft, 1964; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Racism, Religion and Anthropology, Draft, 1947; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Radiation, X-Rays and Fallout, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Random Thoughts on SR/SS, Draft, 1952; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Readings on Race, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 79)
  - Readings on Race, Correspondence, 1941; 1951; 24 items (Box 79)
  - Readings on Race, Table of Contents, 1946; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Readings on Race, Tables and Figures, undated; 18 items (Box 79)
  - Readings on Race, Draft, p. 1-189, undated; 1 item (Box 80)
  - Readings on Race, Draft, p. 190-401, undated; 1 item (Box 80)
  - Readings on Race, Draft, p. 402-623, undated; 1 item (Box 80)
  - Readings on Race, Draft, p. 624-826, undated; 1 item (Box 80)
  - Readings on Race, Draft, p. 827-1037, undated; 1 item (Box 80)
  - Readings on Race, Draft, p. 1038-1178, undated; 1 item (Box 80)
  - A Reconsideration of the Galley Hill Skeleton, Notes, undated; 10 items (Box 79)
  - Reconsideration of the Galley Hill Skeleton, Draft, 1949; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Redheads, Notes, undated; 10 items (Box 79)
  - Redheads, Correspondence, 1963-1981; 9 items (Box 79)
  - Reflections on Violence in America, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Rehumanizing Medicine, Correspondence, 1975; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Religion, Partial Drafts, 1958; undated; 2 items (Box 79)
  - Religion and Science, Correspondence, 1956; 1958; 5 items (Box 79)
  - Remarkable Stone Tool From the Middle Paleolithic, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 79)
  - Remembrance of Howard Gossage, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Renaissance Medicine, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Report of Archaeological Work at Swanscombe and Galley Hill, Kent, England, June to Septemeber 1948, Draft, 1 item (Box 79)
  - Report on Expedition to Swanscombe, Kent, England, 26 May to 13 September, 1948, Draft, 1 item (Box 79)
  - Reproduction, Notes, undated; 22 items (Box 79)
  - Reproduction, Heredity, and Growth, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Reviews, A-D, undated; 56 items (Box 79)
    Reviews by Ashley Montagu of works by: Erwin Ackerknecht, Joy Adamson, Alfred Adler, Ferdinand Anton, Phillip Appleman, Robert Ardrey, W. Arens, Joseg August, Harry Bakwin, Thomas Ban, Victor Barnow, William Battie, Marston Bates, Frank Beach, Alan Bell, Hans-Georg Bendi, Bernard Berelson, Morris Berman, Ronald Berndt, Gerald Berreman, N.J. Berrill, W. Turner Berry, Renato Biasutti, Geoffrey Bibby, David Bidney, Kaj Birket-Smith, L. Jean Bogert, Paul Bohannan, Edith Boyd, Samuel Boyer, Arnold C. Brackman, Myron Brenton, Robert Brown, W.J. Campbell, J.M. Charcot, Suzanne Chevalier-Skolnikoff, I. Chein, Wainwright Churchill, Harvey Cleckley, Yehudi Cohen, J. LeRoy Conel, W.S. Copeman, Carleton Coon, Albert Damon, Charles Darwin, Loyal Davis, Simone DeBeauvoir, Giorgio DeSantillana, Paul Dewald, D.B. Dill, Eric Dingwall, H.D. Disselhoff, Theodosius Dobzhansky, B.T. Donovan, Cora DuBois and Emile Durkheim.
  - Reviews, E-H, undated; 47 items (Box 79)
    Reviews by Ashley Montagu of works by: Editors of Life, Loren Eiseley, Jon Eisenson, Elizabeth Eisenstein, K.R. Eissler, James Fairgrieve, Frank Faulkner, Charles Ferguson, Robin Fox, Gisele Freund, Iago Galdston, Art Gallaher, John Galvin, Sydney Gellis, Edward S. Gifford Jr, Judson Gilbert, Edward Glover, Elizabeth Goldschmidt, Stephen Jay Gould, Henry Gray, Peter Gray, Maurice Green, Arthur Griffin, E.S.E. Hafez, Louis Halle Jr, Mark H. Haller, Marvin Harris, John Harrison, Jacquette Hawkes, Denys Hay, H.R. Hays, F.P. Heald, Alexander Heidel, Fernando Henriques, C. Judson Herrick, Irwin Herskowitz, Jean Hiernaux, Henry Higgs, Norman Himes, Jane Howard, Michael Howell, W. Howells (2 reviews), David Hsia, Francis Hsu, T.H. Huxley and Stanley Hyman.
  - Reviews, I-L, undated; 21 items (Box 79)
    Reviews by Ashley Montagu of works by: S.H. Irvine, Melville Jacobs, Herbert Jennings, Adolf Jensen, Arthur Jensen, Eric Kahler, Abram Kardiner, Pal Kelemen, Alister Kershaw, Helen Koch, Bertram Kraus, Dorothea Leighton, Widukind Lenz, Max Lerner (2 reviews), Elsy Leuzinger, David A. Levitsky, Richard Lewinsohn, Konrad Lorenz (2 reviews)and Frank Lorimer.
  - Reviews, M-P, undated; 37 items (Box 79)
    Reviews by Ashley Montagu of works by: Eleanor MacCoby, William Madsen, Moses Maimonides, Jane Mansbridge, Alfred Marrow, Stella Mason, Jules Masserman, Michael McGiffert, Victor McKusick (3 reviews), H.E.L. Mellersh (2 reviews), J. Edgar Morison, Heinrich Meng, Judson Milburn, Andre Missenard, John Money, Keith Moore, Ramona and Desmond Morris, Robert Moskin, Lois Murphy, Hideo Nishimura, Marvin Opler, Francis Packard, Luigi Pareti, Elizabeth Parker, A.S. Parkes, Nicholas Pastore, Denise Paulme, Albrecht Peiper, Eduard Perhopf, Peter Prince of Greece and Denmark, Ralph Piddington, Stuart Piggott, Adolf Portmann and Magnus Pyke.
  - Reviews, Q-T, undated; 35 items (Box 79)
    Reviews by Ashley Montagu of works by: Barrie Reynolds, Harriet Rheingold, A. Kimball Romney, David Rosenthal, Joseph Roucek, Claude Roy, R.F. Salisbury, John Paul Sartre, J.B.deC.M. Saunders, Aldo Scaglione, Richard E. Scammon, George Schaller, Ernst and Berta Scharrer, Amram Scheinfeld, William J. Schull, Richard H. Schwarz, John Paul Scott, Ralph E. Shikes, Ronald Siegal, Bernard Siegel, George Simpson, Andrew Sinclair, Charles Singer, Edmund Sinnot, E.J. Slijper, J.B. Stanbury, Dorothy Stimson, George Still, Harold Stuart, W.A. Swanberg, Sigfred Taubert, Lynn Thorndike, Jurgen Thornwald, Edward Topsell and Lyn Tornabee.
  - Reviews U-Z and Unattributed, undated; 14 items (Box 79)
    Reviews by Ashley Montagu of works by: J.H. Van der Berg, Edward J. Van Liere, Victor W. Von Hagen, Ornul V. Vorren, Frank Waters, Helena Wayne, J.S. Weiner, Lancelot Law Whyte, George Willey, Roger Williams, Peter J Wilson, Charles Winick, V.C. Wynne-Edwards and unattributed.
  - Reviews and Reviewers, Draft, 1961; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Revolutionary Love, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
  - The Ridicule of Women, Draft, 1954; 1 item (Box 79)
  - Robert Nesbitt, Notes, undated; 8 items (Box 79)
  - Robert Nesbitt, Correspondence, 1951; 1957; 3 items (Box 79)
  - The Salutation of the Dawn, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Say No to Circumcision, Foreword, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Scapula, Notes, 1967; undated; 55 items (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Correspondence, Contributing Authors, 1981-1984; undated; 67 items (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Correspondence, Non-Contributing Authors, 1980-1987; 47 items (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Correspondence, Oxford University Press, 1981-1984; undated; 30 items (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Partial Draft, Boulding, Kenneth E., undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Partial Draft, Fox, Sidney W., 1982; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Partial Drafts, Montagu, Ashley, 1982; 2 items (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Partial Draft, Moyer, Wayne A., 1981; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationsim, Partial Draft, Root-Bernstein, Robert, 1981; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Partial Drafts, Ruse, Michael, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Science and Creationism, Reviews, 1983-1987; undated; 22 items (Box 81)
  - Science and Skin, Abstract, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - The Science of Man, Review, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Science Please, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Science Supports the Sermon on the Mount, Abstract, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - A Scientific Declaration of Faith, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - A Scientist Looks at Love, Draft, undated; 2 items (Box 81)
  - Selection and the Mental Characters of Mankind, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 81)
  - A Semblance of Humanity, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Sequoya, Notes, undated; 4 items (Box 81)
  - Sequoya, Correspondence, 1960; 1961; 3 items (Box 81)
  - Sequoya, Cherokee Indian Genius who Invented an Alphabet and so Brought Literacy to his People, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 81)
  - The Setting for Humanity, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Sex Order of Birth and Personality, 1948; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Should American Men Cry?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Should Your Husband Have Two Wives?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - The Sib., Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - The Significance of Missing and Reduced Upper Lateral Incisor Teeth, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - The Significance of the Tendency Towards the Elimination of the Upper Lateral Incisor Teeth in Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Skeleton Examined at the Court House, White Plains, West Chester, Saturday February 16th, 1935, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - The Skin, Touch, and Human Development, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Skull Planes, Notes, undated; 9 items (Box 81)